<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed_style.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="https://www.rssboard.org/media-rss">
  <channel>
    <title>Wario Ware on .:My Life’s ROMset:. / MartinM</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/wario-ware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wario Ware on .:My Life’s ROMset:. / MartinM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>MartinM - Documenting my life, one ROM at the time.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 22:14:48 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/wario-ware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><icon>http://localhost:1313/logo.png</icon>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgames! (GBA, 2003)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wariowareinc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 22:14:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wariowareinc/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h3 id="warioware-is-weird-it-also-might-be-one-of-my-favorite-nintendo-game-ever">WarioWare is weird. It also might be one of my favorite Nintendo game ever.</h3>
<p>It’s Nintendo embracing its most joyful, off-beat and simply weird nature—a love letter to itself and the medium it shaped.</p>
<p><img src="/images/WarioWare_Box.jpeg" alt="WarioWare, Inc."></p>
<p>I don’t remember much about the game prior to its release. I was aware Nintendo was doing a new game with Wario as its protagonist for the GBA, and that it was a collection of mini-games. I do remember very well is how I got it: one of my aunt–the same aunt that played a pivotal role in my incursion into gaming-wanted me to pick a gift for myself. This was on 2003, meaning San Juan de Dios was the only place I would be able to pick-up a game at a decent price. The game was widely available, but I quickly figured out they were (remarkably good) counterfeit copies. After asking around for an original, I started to dissect the game as you did on your way home: starting from the manual.</p>
<p><img src="/images/WarioWare_Manual.jpeg" alt="WarioWare, Inc."></p>
<p>The manual is just as playful as the game itself: it doesn’t take itself seriously. It has a freaking sticker sheet! It’s written in character for Wario, setting the stage for a game that has embraces its quirks.</p>
<p>WarioWare, Inc. is a game that speaks many game design languages, yet it’s simple and easy to understand. A fast paced collection of fun micro games. A sampler of bite-sized genius. Games being destilled to their core, laid bare. Push A to jump a hotdog. Pres A to catch a stick being dropped. Find the cat. Move the realistic Japanese person and bounce watermelons. Press A repeteadly to reel in the snot from the princess. Play 4 seconds of F-Zero. 200+ microgames that can stand on its own.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mrs_6tFPoGo">Why is there an Enka song?</a> Why it works so well as the backdrop of this frenzy? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9xCdOCp5uG0">Why is &lsquo;Drifting Away&rsquo; so freaking good?</a> “Your golden-colored coupe, looks like it has butter spread all over it”? What is this dreamy nonsense…</p>
<p>It’s also, in both ways, an implicit and explicit love letter to all things Nintendo. Yes, there’s a whole category of games taken from mechanics from classic Nintendo games&hellip; and then it goes to the deep end, celebrating such deep cuts as <a href="https://nintendo.fandom.com/wiki/Color_TV-Racing_112">Color TV-Racing 112</a>.</p>
<p>I love how authentic WarioWare, Inc. is. Unique, yet laser-focused on its goal: a collection of simple games that can be played on the go, on short sessions.</p>
<p>Hirofumi Matsuoka is credited as Director, and by looking at the games he has been part of, I can draw a line joining some of favorite games from that time: Mario Paint, Warioland 4 and WarioWare, Inc. while I have never played the Mario Artist games (I yet have to dip my feet on the 64DD library), but I can see glimpses of the quirkiness that makes WarioWare so special.</p>
<p>Maybe we all need to pull-off a WarioWare in our lives: be unapologetically authentic and fun, just for the sake of it.</p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
