<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/feed_style.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="https://www.rssboard.org/media-rss">
  <channel>
    <title>.:My Life’s ROMset:. / MartinM</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on .:My Life’s ROMset:. / MartinM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>MartinM - Documenting my life, one ROM at the time.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 22:14:48 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><icon>http://localhost:1313/logo.png</icon>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WarioWare, Inc.: Mega Microgames! (GBA, 2003)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wariowareinc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 22:14:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wariowareinc/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h3 id="warioware-is-weird-it-also-might-be-one-of-my-favorite-nintendo-game-ever">WarioWare is weird. It also might be one of my favorite Nintendo game ever.</h3>
<p>It’s Nintendo embracing its most joyful, off-beat and simply weird nature—a love letter to itself and the medium it shaped.</p>
<p><img src="/images/WarioWare_Box.jpeg" alt="WarioWare, Inc."></p>
<p>I don’t remember much about the game prior to its release. I was aware Nintendo was doing a new game with Wario as its protagonist for the GBA, and that it was a collection of mini-games. I do remember very well is how I got it: one of my aunt–the same aunt that played a pivotal role in my incursion into gaming-wanted me to pick a gift for myself. This was on 2003, meaning San Juan de Dios was the only place I would be able to pick-up a game at a decent price. The game was widely available, but I quickly figured out they were (remarkably good) counterfeit copies. After asking around for an original, I started to dissect the game as you did on your way home: starting from the manual.</p>
<p><img src="/images/WarioWare_Manual.jpeg" alt="WarioWare, Inc."></p>
<p>The manual is just as playful as the game itself: it doesn’t take itself seriously. It has a freaking sticker sheet! It’s written in character for Wario, setting the stage for a game that has embraces its quirks.</p>
<p>WarioWare, Inc. is a game that speaks many game design languages, yet it’s simple and easy to understand. A fast paced collection of fun micro games. A sampler of bite-sized genius. Games being destilled to their core, laid bare. Push A to jump a hotdog. Pres A to catch a stick being dropped. Find the cat. Move the realistic Japanese person and bounce watermelons. Press A repeteadly to reel in the snot from the princess. Play 4 seconds of F-Zero. 200+ microgames that can stand on its own.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mrs_6tFPoGo">Why is there an Enka song?</a> Why it works so well as the backdrop of this frenzy? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9xCdOCp5uG0">Why is &lsquo;Drifting Away&rsquo; so freaking good?</a> “Your golden-colored coupe, looks like it has butter spread all over it”? What is this dreamy nonsense…</p>
<p>It’s also, in both ways, an implicit and explicit love letter to all things Nintendo. Yes, there’s a whole category of games taken from mechanics from classic Nintendo games&hellip; and then it goes to the deep end, celebrating such deep cuts as <a href="https://nintendo.fandom.com/wiki/Color_TV-Racing_112">Color TV-Racing 112</a>.</p>
<p>I love how authentic WarioWare, Inc. is. Unique, yet laser-focused on its goal: a collection of simple games that can be played on the go, on short sessions.</p>
<p>Hirofumi Matsuoka is credited as Director, and by looking at the games he has been part of, I can draw a line joining some of favorite games from that time: Mario Paint, Warioland 4 and WarioWare, Inc. while I have never played the Mario Artist games (I yet have to dip my feet on the 64DD library), but I can see glimpses of the quirkiness that makes WarioWare so special.</p>
<p>Maybe we all need to pull-off a WarioWare in our lives: be unapologetically authentic and fun, just for the sake of it.</p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fortune on Packardbell 95</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fortuneonpackardbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 10:34:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fortuneonpackardbell/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Neat site I found today: <a href="https://packardbell95.com/fortune/">https://packardbell95.com/fortune/</a></p>
<p>A furtune telling machine for the vaporwave soul.</p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Fight (1989 - Arcade (CPS1))</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/finalfight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/finalfight/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/codywalk.gif" alt="Final Fight"></p>
<p>One of my earliest memories is that of  the arcade on the upper floor of Plaza Patria, above Musical Lemus. This was a few years before Diversiones Moy opened on the first floor. I remember a few titles including a full-sized Hang-On, After Burner II, Pit Fighter,  TMNT 2, and Final Fight. I must have been 4 years old and I found what might be my first ‘favorite’ game.</p>
<p>There was something incredibly alluring: big characters, sound effects that distinguished themselves clearly over the rest, and gameplay I could wrap my head around at a very young age: move total the right, punch baddies. That was it.</p>
<p>The attract screen was too good to ignore: a poignant synth ‘wam-wam-babawam-babawam’, the phone ringing, mayor Mike Haggar (‘He looks like my grandpa!’ I told many times to my father), the menacing grin of Damnd… the game is filled with little details that are as stiking today as they were decades ago. Somehow the &lsquo;Continue?&rsquo; showing our heroes tied with lit dynamite in front of them, waiting you to save them by putting another coin is truly efective.</p>

    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iVZ8UxS_JLM?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<p>Why is it that punching the same enemies over and over again is so satisfying? Why breaking a phone booth or a trash can with your bare hands feels so rewarding? Even at that young age I understood the allure of it: it’s an universal power fantasy—good vs. evil.</p>
<p>I was too young to understand the media and cultural context it was inspired by (‘The Warriors’, the New York of the 80’s) or the history behind it (Final Fight was originally called ‘Street Fighter 89’, the foundation built by Capcom that eventually would become Street Fighter II). Nevertheless, it planted a seed.</p>
<p><img src="/images/finalfight-2.png" alt="Final Fight"></p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Persona 4 Golden</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/persona4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/persona4/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/persona4_1.gif" alt="Persona 4 Intro"></p>
<p>I’ve always though video games can be an effective medium to convey certain stories and emotions. Persona 4 does a magnificent job at it. This is a game that came to my life in a pretty interesting time and which managed to do two things: rekindle my passion for story driven games and give me some perspective regarding my life.</p>
<p>Persona 4 is a game I wouldn’t have played in normal circumstances: A 60+ hours JRPG with Anime aesthetic and tropes. This description alone made it an unappealing proposition at the time—I’ve became more selective in terms of which game I play. However, I’ve heard in the past so much about the game and how good it was from people I knew shared very similar taste in games. Seeing the game on sale on PSN was the last push I needed.</p>
<p>“Role Playing Game” is a term that defines Persona 4 in the literal sense, and not in what we expect from the term nowadays. During my whole experience I was compelled to play a “role” and immerse myself in the setting; The protagonist is a shell meant to be filled by you, the player, in that setting. This is one of the key aspects that made the amalgamation of gameplay, story and themes feel meaningful throughout my experience.</p>
<p>The greatest achievement of Persona 4 is how it manages to combine a theme (‘finding your true self’) with gameplay elements and the stories of the characters. Borrowing heavily from Jungian psychology, Persona 4 presents you a setting in which each character has its own story arch dealing with the ‘finding your true self’ theme. By making story and character progression a essential factor in gameplay flow, Persona 4 actively drives players into the narrative construct. This proved to be a quite powerful narrative technique as it made me genuinely “care” about the characters. Yosuke, Chie, Yukiko, Kanji, Rise, Naoto, Dojima, Nanako, Marie… their history, tied to the particular Arcana they represented, drove me to continue playing. I would spend each in game day actually thinking hard on how I would spend time with the characters, instead of just going through the motions. This is were the magic happened: gameplay and story went hand in hand, complementing each other.</p>
<p>What I described in the last paragraph wouldn’t be as powerful and motive enough if it weren&rsquo;t for the fabulous soundtrack (According to Last.fm, I’ve 1,000+ scrobbles), the polished-to-shine presentation, the gorgeous looking UI, and amazing character design. The overall package is quite refined.</p>
<p>I started playing Persona 4 shortly after I decided to start an entrepreneurial venture along with some of the most talented people I’ve encountered in the past years. At the time, it made me realize how lucky I am for being around the people that care for me. When dealing with challenges, the best support I have is right there, next to me: my family, my friends, my peers… they all play a very important role in how I face challenges and define a big part of who am I. Persona 4 made me reflect about the importance that people around me have.</p>
<p>And, for the record…</p>
<p>#TeamChie</p>
<p><img src="/images/p4g_boxart_rp.jpg" alt="Persona 4 Golden Boxart"></p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Hello reader! I hope you are doing great. This is me, once again shouting to the void. But this time it feels a bit different.</p>
<p>First, a bit context for why am I doing this. I stumbled into <a href="https://lmnt.me/">Louie Mantia’s blog</a> a few weeks ago and a <a href="https://lmnt.me/blog/reclamation.html">some things</a> <a href="https://lmnt.me/blog/creating-for-myself.html">started to resonate</a> with me. Louie has been an artist I have admired for a good chunk of my life, creating beautiful icons and wallpapers that I’ve used over the years. His written words have set in motion a plan that I had in the back of my mind for a while.</p>
<p>I’m 35. The internet came into my life at around 10. Throughout my life online, I’ve always been fascinated with the idea of freely share information and just put it out there. To this day, I still have tons of respect for the people that do it. I tried a few times to have some sort of thought repository, but ultimately I ended up taking them down.</p>
<p>I became very aware over the past few months about the notion of everything we do or share online is no longer -ours-. It belongs to whatever platform you use. Somehow, I miss the sentiment of the internet being built by regular folks——like you and me. This is me, bringing back a small piece of the internet that has meant a lot over the years. For me, first and foremost, but also to share with the world as is.</p>
<h2 id="why-my-lifes-romset">Why “My Life’s ROMset?”</h2>
<p>A ROM (Read-Only Memory) file contains the data that makes up a video game in the context of emulation. A ROMset is a collection of the individual ROM files that comprise a set of games available for a particular platform. I like to think as this written experiences that I intend to post here as ROMs from my life. I also want to write about the video games that have ment something in my life, but from my particular context. ‘Pit Fighter’ might be a really shitty fighting game, but turns out it’s one of my earliest memories and it’s tied to core memories of my father taking me to the arcade on weekends.</p>
<p>Thanks for stopping by. I wish you the best.</p>
<p>MartinM</p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:55:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="hi">Hi!</h1>
<p>You have reached the personal space of MartinM. This is just a remporary placeholder while we get it up to snuff. Thanks for swinging by!</p>
]]></description>
      
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
